Guide to the Morse Hardware Company records 1891-1999
Western Washington University, Center for Pacific Northwest Studies
- Morse Hardware Company, 1884-1994; Series I
  - Financial Records, 1884-1979; Sub-series 3
    - Cash Journals
      - Cash Journal (Organized by month), 1961-1965 (Volume 120)
    - Daybooks (Blotters)
      - Daybook, February 5, 1886- April 7, 1887 (Volume 121)
      - Daybook, January 13, 1887- June 18, 1888 (Volume 122)
      - Daybook, August 18 to November 30, 1887 (Volume 123)
      - Daybook, April to July 1888 (Volume 124)
      - Daybook, May to December 1888 (Volume 125)
      - Daybook, June 1 to July 31, 1888 (Volume 126)
      - Daybook, August 1 to October 4, 1888 (Volume 127)
      - Daybook, October to November 1888 (Volume 128)
      - Daybook, November 1888 to January 1889 (Volume 129)
      - Daybook, December 1888 to March 1889 (Volume 130)
      - Daybook, December 1888 to September 1889 (Volume 131)
      - Daybook, February 8 to March 6, 1889 (Volume 132)
      - Daybook, March to April 1889 (Volume 133)
      - Daybook, March 30 to April 1889 (Volume 134)
      - Daybook, April 22 to May 1889 (MWF) (Volume 135)
      - Daybook, April to June 1889 (TTHS) (Volume 136)
      - Daybook, June to July 1889 (TTHS) (Volume 137)
      - Daybook, July 15 to September 10, 1889 (Volume 138)
      - Daybook, September 1 to December 19, 1889 (Volume 139)
      - Daybook, September 11 to November 5, 1889 (Volume 140)
      - Daybook, October 7, 1889 to March 1, 1890 (Volume 141)
      - Daybook, December 1889 to January 1891 (Volume 142)
      - Daybook, March 10 to August 28, 1890 (Volume 143)
      - Daybook, April 19 to October 21, 1890 (Volume 144)
      - Daybook, April 24 to October 11, 1890 (Volume 145)
      - Daybook, September 1, 1890 to February 14, 1891 (Volume 146)
      - Daybook, October 25, 1890 to March 21, 1891 (Volume 147)
      - Daybook, March to October 1891 (Volume 148)
      - Daybook, March to October 1891 (Volume 149)
      - Daybook, March 1891 to May 1892 (Volume 150)
      - Daybook, October 1891 to April 1892 (Volume 151)
      - Daybook, October 12, 1891 to May 17, 1892 (Volume 152)
      - Daybook, May 18, 1892 to January 25, 1893 (Volume 153)
      - Daybook, May 19, 1892 to February 13, 1893 (TTHS) (Volume 154)
      - Daybook, May 1892 to May 1893 (Volume 155)
      - Daybook, February 13 to August 11, 1893 (MWF) (Volume 156)
      - Daybook, February 14 to August 21, 1893 (TTHS) (Volume 157)
      - Daybook, June 1, 1893 to September 14, 1894 (Volume 158)
      - Daybook, August 22, 1893 to June 16, 1894 (TTHS) (Volume 159)
      - Daybook, August 23, 1893 to June 13, 1894 (MWF) (Volume 160)
      - Daybook, June to December 1894 (MWF) (Volume 161)
      - Daybook, June 19 to December 18, 1894 (TTHS) (Volume 162)
      - Daybook, September 1894 to December 1895 (Volume 163)
      - Daybook, December 22 to December 31, 1894 (Volume 164)
      - Daybook, January to September 1895 (TTHS) (Volume 165)
      - Daybook, January to September 1895 (MWF) (Volume 166)
      - Daybook, October 1 to August 6, 1895 (MWF) (Volume 167)
      - Daybook, October to July 1895 (TTHS) (Volume 168)
      - Daybook (Labeled “cash sales”), January 1, 1896 to January 30, 1897 (Volume 169)
      - Daybook, August 6, 1896 to January 9, 1897 (Volume 170)
      - Daybook, January 11 to May 20, 1897 (Volume 171)
      - Daybook, November 15, 1897 to May 16, 1898 (MWF) (Volume 172)
      - Daybook, November 16, 1897 to May 17, 1898 (TTHS) (Volume 173)
      - Daybook, May 19 to October 22, 1898 (TTHS) (Volume 174)
      - Daybook, October 24 to April 17, 1898 (MWF) (Volume 175)
      - Daybook, October 25 to April 18, 1898 (TTHS) (Volume 176)
      - Daybook, April 18 to August 17, 1899 (TTHS) (Volume 177)
      - Daybook, August to December 1899 (MWF) (Volume 178)
      - Daybook, August 19 to December 1899 (TTHS) (Volume 179)
      - Daybook, January 1 to April 13, 1900 (MWF) (Volume 180)
      - Daybook, January 2 to April 14, 1900 (TTHS) (Volume 181)
      - Daybook, April 16 to July 6, 1900 (MWF) (Volume 182)
      - Daybook, April 17 to July 5, 1900 (TTHS) (Volume 183)
      - Daybook, July 7 to October 16, 1900 (TTHS) (Volume 184)
      - Daybook, July 9 to October 17, 1900 (MWF) (Volume 185)
    - Traveling Men's Sales Reports: Customer Calls by Salesmen
      - Sales Reports, October 1910- June 1911 (Volume 186)
      - Sales Reports, November 1910- April 1912 (Volume 187)
      - Sales Reports, May 1912- June 1913 (Volume 188)
      - Sales Reports, June 1913- May 1914 (Volume 189)
      - Sales Reports, May 1914- April 1915 (Volume 190)
      - Sales Reports, April 1915- April 1916 (Volume 191)
      - Sales Reports, April 1916- May 1917 (Volume 192)
      - Sales Reports, May 1917- January 1918 (Volume 193)
    - Trial Balance Ledgers
      - Ledger, 1895-1897 (Volume 194)
      - Ledger, 1897-1918 (Volume 195)
      - Ledger, 1919-1932 (Volume 196)
      - Ledger, 1933-1937 (Volume 197)
      - Ledger, 1938-1947 (Volume 198)
    - Other Financial Records
      - “Gross Margin Calculations” (Alphabetical by company name), 1954-1956 (Volume 199)
      - Ledger of accounts of raw and boiled linseed oil, 1933-1943 (Volume 200)
      - “Payable Commercial Paper”, 1937-1938 (Volume 201)
      - “Notes and Bills Payable”, 1890 (Volume 202)
      - “Shop Book”, October 1889 to January 1890 (Volume 203)
      - “Estimate Book”, 1894 (Volume 204)
      - “Floor Cash Book”, 1887 (Volume 205)
      - “Freight Book”, 1885 (Volume 206)
      - “Shipping Register”, 1889 (Volume 207)
    - Financial Records Re: Bellingham Bay and British Columbia Railroad
      - “Sales Book”, 1886-1887 (Volume 208)
      - “Wharf Book”, 1886 (Volume 209)
      - “Shipping Receipts”, 1892 (Volume 210)
      - “Shipping Receipts”, 1893 (Volume 211)
    - Financial Records Re: Great Northern Railroad
      - “Shipping Receipts”, August 1892- May 1894 (Volume 212)
      - “Shipping Receipts”, January to November 1894 (Volume 213)
      - “Shipping Receipts”, November to December 1894 (Volume 214)
      - Shipping Receipts, 1887-1889 (Volume 215)
      - Shipping Receipts, 1889 (Volume 216)
      - Shipping Receipts, 1890 (Volume 217)
    - Morse Hardware Check Registers
      - Check Registers, 1889-1890 (Volume 218)
      - Check Registers, 1891 (Volume 219)
      - Inventories, 1890 (Volume 220)
      - Inventories, 1892 (Volume 221)
      - Inventories, 1893 (Volume 222)
      - Inventories, 1895 (Volume 223)
      - “Charged Off Accounts Received” (boxed), 1921-1937 (Volume 224)
      - Old Charged Off Notes Receivable, circa 1900-1935 (Box-folder 5/18)
      - Old Charged Off Notes Receivable, circa 1900-1935 (Box-folder 5/19)
    - Charges Offs, 1915 (Box-folder 5/20)
    - Notes, Collections and Charge Offs, Undated (Box-folder 5/21)
    - Financial Forms and Receipts, 1890-1917 (Box-folder 5/22)
    - Expenses, 1920-1970 (Box-folder 5/23)
    - Clients and Charges, 1920-1933 (Box-folder 5/24)
    - Product Order Book, undated (Box-folder 5/25)
    - Vehicle Information Book, circa. 1927 (Box-folder 5/26)
    - City Bills
      - A-B, 1891 (Box-folder 6/1)
      - C-H, 1891 (Box-folder 6/2)
      - I-O, 1891 (Box-folder 6/3)
      - P, January 1891; July to September 1891 (Box-folder 6/4)
      - P, October to December 1891 (Box-folder 6/5)
      - Q-Z, 1891 (Box-folder 6/6)
      - A, 1892 (Box-folder 6/7)
      - B, January to May 1892 (Box-folder 6/7)
      - B, June to September 1892 (Box-folder 6/8)
      - B, October to December 1892 (Box-folder 6/9)
      - C-E, 1892 (Box-folder 6/10)
      - F-G, 1892 (Box-folder 6/11)
      - H-K, 1892 (Box-folder 6/12)
      - L-O, 1892 (Box-folder 6/13)
      - P, January to May 1892 (Box-folder 6/14)
      - P, June to December 1892 (Box-folder 6/15)
      - R, 1892 (Box-folder 6/16)
      - S, January to May 1892 (Box-folder 6/16)
      - S, June to December 1892 (Box-folder 6/17)
      - T-Z, 1892 (Box-folder 6/18)
      - general, January 1893 (Box-folder 6/19)
      - general, 1895 (Box-folder 6/20)
      - A, 1896 (Box-folder 6/21)
      - B, January to August 1896 (Box-folder 6/21)
      - B, September to December 1896 (Box-folder 6/22)
      - C-E, 1896 (Box-folder 6/23)
      - F-H, 1896 (Box-folder 6/24)
      - I-S, 1896 (Box-folder 6/25)
      - T-Z, 1896 (Box-folder 6/26)
      - A-C, 1897 (Box-folder 6/27)
      - D-Q, 1897 (Box-folder 6/28)
      - R-Z, 1897 (Box-folder 6/29)
      - Freight Bills, December 1891-March 1892 (Box-folder 6/30)
      - Freight Bills, April 1892 (Box-folder 6/31)
      - Freight Bills, May 1892 (Box-folder 6/32)
      - Freight Bills, June 1892 (Box-folder 6/33)
      - Freight Bills, July 1-19, 1892 (Box-folder 6/34)
      - Freight Bills, July 20-31, 1892 (Box-folder 6/35)
      - Freight Bills, August 1-15 (Box-folder 6/36)
      - Freight Bills, August 16-31, 1892 (Box-folder 6/37)
      - Freight Bills, September 1-15, 1892 (Box-folder 6/38)
      - Freight Bills, September 16-31, 1892 (Box-folder 6/39)
      - Freight Bills, October 1-15, 1892 (Box-folder 6/40)
      - Freight Bills, October 16-31, 1892 (Box-folder 6/41)
      - Freight Bills, November 1892 (Box-folder 6/42)
      - Freight Bills, December 1-15, 1892 (Box-folder 6/43)
      - Freight Bills, December 16-31, 1892 (Box-folder 6/44)
    - Valuable Receipts
      - Valuable Receipts, January to December 1891 (Box-folder 6/45)
      - Valuable Receipts, January 1892 (Box-folder 6/46)
      - Valuable Receipts, February 1892 (Box-folder 6/47)
      - Valuable Receipts, March 1892 (Box-folder 6/48)
      - Valuable Receipts, April 1892 (Box-folder 6/49)
      - Valuable Receipts, May 1892 (Box-folder 6/50)
      - Valuable Receipts, June 1892 (Box-folder 6/51)
      - Valuable Receipts, July 1892 (Box-folder 6/52)
      - Valuable Receipts, August 1892 (Box-folder 6/53)
      - Valuable Receipts, September 1892 (Box-folder 6/54)
      - Valuable Receipts, October 1892 (Box-folder 6/55)
      - Valuable Receipts, November 1892 (Box-folder 6/56)
      - Valuable Receipts, December 1892-January 1893 (Box-folder 6/57)
      - A-B, 1895 (Box-folder 6/58)
      - C-D, 1895 (Box-folder 6/59)
      - E-G, 1895 (Box-folder 6/60)
      - H-K, 1895 (Box-folder 6/61)
      - L-M, 1895 (Box-folder 6/62)
      - N-R, 1895 (Box-folder 6/63)
      - S, 1895 (Box-folder 6/64)
      - T-Z, 1895 (Box-folder 6/65)
    - Bills of Lading, Shingles
      - Bills of Lading, February to April 1894 (Box-folder 7/1)
      - Bills of Lading, September 1894 (Box-folder 7/2)
      - Bills of Lading, October 1894 (Box-folder 7/3)
      - Bills of Lading, November 1894 (Box-folder 7/4)
      - Bills of Lading, December 1894 (Box-folder 7/5)
      - Bills of Lading, January 1895 (Box-folder 7/6)
      - Bills of Lading, February 1895 (Box-folder 7/7)
      - Bills of Lading, March 1895 (Box-folder 7/8)
      - Bills of Lading, April 1895 (Box-folder 7/9)
      - Bills of Lading, May 1895 (Box-folder 7/10)
      - Bills of Lading, June 1895 (Box-folder 7/11)
      - Bills of Lading, July 1895 (Box-folder 7/12)
      - Bills of Lading, August 1895 (Box-folder 7/13)
      - Bills of Lading, September 1895 (Box-folder 7/14)
      - Bills of Lading, October 1895 (Box-folder 7/15)
      - Bills of Lading, November 1895 (Box-folder 7/16)
      - Bills of Lading, December 1895 (Box-folder 7/17)
    - Taxes
      - Personal Property Assessments, 1960-1973 (Box-folder 7/18)
      - Personal Property Assessments, 1963-1971 (Box-folder 7/19)
      - Real Estate, 1963-1979 (Box-folder 7/20)
      - Statements Made to County Assessor, 1920-1959 (Box-folder 7/21)
    - Financial Records labeled “Monthly Records", 1931-1960 (Box-folder 7/22)
    - Powder Price Lists and Correspondence Re: Blasting
      - Price Lists and Correspondence, 1940-1954 (Box-folder 7/23)
      - Price Lists and Correspondence, 1946-1957 (Box-folder 7/24)
    - Altas Powder Company
      - Leases and cancellations, 1920-1955 (Box-folder 7/25)
      - Agreement and Prices, 1935-1952 (Box-folder 7/26)
    - Materials regarding the building of Powder House
      - Bakerview Road (Includes photos), 1929-1956 (Box-folder 7/27)
      - Construction, 1940 (Box-folder 7/28)
      - Canfield Addition, 1931-1941 (Box-folder 7/29)
      - Meridian and city limits, 1893-1920 (Box-folder 7/30)
      - Powder and blasting information, Undated (Box-folder 7/31)
    - Wenatchee Steel Business (puchased by Morse Hardware in 1989) (Box-folder 7/32)
    - Tacoma Industrial Steel, Undated (Box-folder 7/33)
    - Roche Harbor Lime and Cement Company
      - Letters and Harvest Festival invitations, 1921-1932 (Box-folder 7/34)
      - Pamphlets, 1921-1935 (Box-folder 7/35)
    - Special Insurance Information, Undated (Box-folder 7/36)
  - Employees and Employee Functions, 1893-1991; Sub-series 4
    - Employees, 1923-1991 (Box-folder 7/37)
    - Employee Lists, 1937-1958 (Box-folder 7/38)
    - Employee Rating Forms A-Z, 1944-1945 (Box-folder 7/39)
    - Operational Procedures and Bulletins for employees, 1959-1966 (Box-folder 8/1)
    - Invitations to Christmas Parties and other Special Events held for employees
      - Invitations, 1934-1988 (Box-folder 8/2)
      - Invitations, 1980-1993 (Box-folder 8/3)
    - Job Descriptions & Objections, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 8/4)
    - Retirement party for Pearl Brogden, November 1991 (Box-folder 8/5)
    - Bound Volumes, Relating to Employees and their functions
        - Time Books, October 1893 to April 1905 (Volume 225)
        - Time Books, May 1905 to December 1906 (Volume 226)
        - Time Books, August 1907 to November 1911 (Volume 227)
        - Time Books, December 1909 to February 1912 (Volume 228)
        - Time Books, March 1912 to May 1914 (Volume 229)
        - Time Books, June 1914 to September 1916 (Volume 230)
        - Time Books, October 1916 to December 1918 (Volume 231)
        - Time Books, January 1919 to December 1920 (Volume 232)
        - Application Office Employees Wage Schedule, 1943 (Volume 233)
        - Employee Record, 1909 (Volume 234)
  - Merchandise, Advertising and Customer Relations, 1892-1994; Sub-series 5:
    - Marketing Calendar, 1989 (Box-folder 8/6)
    - Booklets for Customer Promotion, circa 1970-1990 (Box-folder 8/7)
    - “Morse Matters” Newsletters for customers, 1988-1994 (Box-folder 8/8)
    - Customer Relations for Morse Hardware's early history, Undated (Box-folder 8/9)
    - Sentry-Distribution America, 1992 (Box-folder 8/10)
    - Report- “The Wholesale Hardware Catalog: A Report by the Catalog Committee of the National Wholesale Hardware Association”, September 1967 (Box-folder 8/11)
    - Small Hardware Catalogs, Undated (Box-folder 8/12)
    - Catalogs
      - American Window Glass, 1916; 1924 (Box-folder 8/13)
      - Art Metal Construction Co. “Modulars”- work stations, Undated (Box-folder 8/13)
      - CC Belknap Glass Co., 1914; 1931 (Box-folder 8/13)
      - Columbia Steel Company, 1935 (Box-folder 8/13)
      - Great Majestic Ranges, Undated (Box-folder 8/13)
      - Morse Hardware “Marine Hardware Boat Equipment”, 1948 (Box-folder 8/13)
      - M.R. Campbell Inc., 1918 (Box-folder 8/14)
      - Pacific Northwest Millwork Catalogue, 1927 (Box-folder 8/14)
      - Pacific Universal Catalog, 1916; 1920; 1923 (Box-folder 8/14)
      - W.P. Fuller and Company, 1903 (Box-folder 8/14)
      - Seaside Industries, 1968; 1969 (Box-folder 8/14)
      - Stock Millwork Catalog, 1939 (Box-folder 8/14)
    - Merchandise Shows, 1983-1990 (Box-folder 8/15)
    - Want Books (8 varying in size), Undated (Box-folder 8/16)
    - Advertising- Merchandise Fliers, Undated (Box-folder 8/17)
    - Hungerford Genuine Bronze Screen Cloth, Undated (Box-folder 8/18)
    - “The Great Majestic Range Cookbook,”, circa 1920's-1930's (Box-folder 8/19)
    - Horse Whips and Buggies available from Morse Hardware, Undated (Box-folder 8/20)
    - Johnson “Sea Horse 5 1/2” Model CD (Outboard Motor), Undated (Box-folder 8/21)
    - Yardsticks-Invoices and Advertising, 1921-1949 (Box-folder 8/22)
    - Newpaper Advertisement for the First Baptist Church Ladies Sale held at Morse Hardware, December 15, 1910 (Box-folder 8/23)
    - List of Customer Accounts, 1920's (Box-folder 8/24)
    - Order Form (sample), Undated (Box-folder 8/25)
    - Orders
      - Morrison Mill, 1914-1935 (Box-folder 8/26)
      - Pacific American Fisheries, 1901 (Box-folder 8/27)
      - Fish Trap Netting orders and List of Cannery Companies, 1958; pre-1916 (Box-folder 8/28)
      - Customer Requisitions and Orders, March 1892; Undated (Box-folder 8/29)
      - Customer Requisitions and Orders, April 1892 (Box-folder 8/30)
      - Customer Requisitions and Orders, May to June 1892 (Box-folder 8/31)
      - Customer Requisitions and Orders, July to August 1892 (Box-folder 8/32)
      - Customer Requisitions and Orders, September to October 1892 (Box-folder 8/33)
      - Customer Requisitions and Orders, November to December 1892 (Box-folder 8/34)
      - Customer Requisitions and Orders, January to February 1893; Undated (Box-folder 8/35)
      - Customer Requisitions and Orders, March to May 1893 (Box-folder 8/36)
      - Customer Requisitions and Orders, June to August 1893 (Box-folder 8/37)
      - Customer Requisitions and Orders, September to October 1893 (Box-folder 8/38)
      - Customer Requisitions and Orders, November to December 1893 (Box-folder 8/39)
    - Pamphlet- “Hardware Selling Kinks” by Roy F. Soule, 1913 (Box-folder 9/1)
    - Pamphlets- Relating to individual companies
      - Clear Lake Lumber Company “A Timber and Sawmill Travelog”, Undated (Box-folder 9/2)
      - Jensen Byrd Company “100th Anniversary Special Edition”, 1983 (Box-folder 9/2)
      - Ketchikan Pulp Company “…Our First 20 Years”, 1974 (Box-folder 9/2)
      - Orcas Power and Light Company “Northeaster '89”, 1989 (Box-folder 9/2)
      - San Juan County Bank “85 Years of Service”, 1978 (Box-folder 9/2)
      - Skagit Corporation “Pictoral”, 1962 (Box-folder 9/2)
      - Snoqualamie Falls Lumber Company “Snoqualamie Falls Lumber Company”, 1925 (Box-folder 9/2)
    - Pamphlets- Relating to Concrete
      - “Building Re-enforced Concrete Silos”, 1914 (Box-folder 9/3)
      - “Concrete Highway Magazine”, 1917 (Box-folder 9/3)
      - “Concrete in Home Sanitation”, Undated (Box-folder 9/3)
      - “Foundation Walls and Basements of Concrete”, Undated (Box-folder 9/3)
      - “Permanent Construction Around the House and on the Farm”, 1914 (Box-folder 9/3)
    - Periodicals
      - “Do It Yourself Retailing,”, June 1986; July 1987; December 1988; October 1989 (Box-folder 9/4)
      - “Hardware World”, November 1954; November 1956; July 1959 (Box-folder 9/5)
    - Books
      - Business Ideas Handbook by the Editorial Staff of Prentice-Hall, 1949 (Box-folder 9/6)
      - Hardware Window Advertising by Roy F. Soule, 1914 (Box-folder 9/7)
      - How to Evaluate Hardware Store Locations by Dwayne Laws, 1971 (Box-folder 9/8)
      - How to Sell Hardware by Roy F. Soule, 1912 (Box-folder 9/9)
      - Letters that Land Orders by John Horace Lytle, 1911 (Box-folder 9/10)
      - Making Him Pay: Exemplifying the Evolution of Conciliation by Henry C. Lawrence, 1908 (Box-folder 9/11)
      - Merchandise Rating Register: Hardware Merchants of the World 1922 Compiled by Hardware Dealers Magazine (Box-folder 9/12)
      - The Modern Hardware Store ed. by Carl W. Dipman, 1929 (Box-folder 9/13)
      - New Collection Methods: A Systematic Treatment of the Place of Collections in Marketing by Edward Hall Gardner, 1919 (Box-folder 9/14)
      - Price Maintenance by Thomas A Fernley, 1912 (Box-folder 9/15)
      - Retail and Wholesale Trade by Domestic Distribution Department, Chamber of Commerce of the United States, 1928 (Box-folder 9/16)
      - Survey of Retailing Practices: Practical Plans and Methods for Meeting the New Competition: Volume I, by the Dartnell Corporation, 1931 (Box-folder 9/17)
      - Survey of Retailing Practices: Practical Plans and Methods for Meeting the New Competition: Volume II, by the Dartnell Corporation, 1931 (Box-folder 9/18)
    - Bound Volumes, Merchandise, Advertising and Customer Relations
        - Catalog (Labeled as the first catalog), 1898 (Volume 235)
        - Catalog, 1920 (Volume 236)
        - Catalog, 1920 (Volume 237)
        - Catalog (Salesman's copy), 1937 (Volume 238)
        - Catalog, 1937 (Volume 239)
        - Catalog, 1937 (Volume 240)
        - Catalog (Salesman's copy), 1938 (Volume 241)
        - Catalog (Salesman's copy), 1943 (Volume 242)
        - Catalog, 1955 (Volume 243)
        - Catalog, 1955 (Volume 244)
        - Catalog, 1960-1962 (Volume 245)
        - Catalog (With monthly dividers), 1963 (Volume 246)
        - Catalog, 1964-1966 (Volume 247)
        - Catalog, 1967-1969 (Volume 248)
        - Catalog, 1970-1971 (Volume 249)
        - Catalog, 1971-1972 (Volume 250)
        - Catalog (Labelled as "frozen"), 1973 (Volume 251)
        - Catalog, 1986 (Volume 252)
        - Catalog, 1994 (Volume 253)
        - Price List Book, 1899 (Volume 254)
        - Price List Book, 1904 (Volume 255)
        - Price List Book, 1984 (Volume 256)
        - Order Checking Sheets, 1942-1944 (Volume 257)
        - Order Checking Sheets, 1945-1948 (Volume 258)
        - Order Checking Sheets, 1956-1958 (Volume 259)
      - Lists of Recipients of Morse Hardware Catalogs
        - Catalog Recipient List (Alphabetical listing), 1920-1921 (Volume 260)
        - Catalog Recipient List (Numerical listing), 1920-1921 (Volume 261)
        - Catalog Recipient List (Alphabetical listing), 1939 (Volume 262)
        - Catalog Recipient List (Numerical listing), 1939 (Volume 263)
        - Catalog Recipient List (Numerical listing), February 1953- March 1966 (Volume 264)
        - Catalog Recipient List (Numbers 5000-5075), August 1966- November 1972 (Volume 265)
        - Catalog Recipient List (Numbers 1816-2479), August 1966- December 1974 (Volume 266)
        - Catalog Recipient List (Numbers 1-892), January 1973- August 1993 (Volume 267)
        - Catalog Recipient List (Numbers 1000-3470), January 1973- January 1994 (Volume 268)
        - Catalog Recipient List (A-Z), Undated (Volume 269)
        - Bound volume of Majestic Range Company advertisements, Undated (Volume 270)
        - Blank book titled “Records”, Undated (Volume 271)
  - Subject Files, 1890-1994; Sub-series 6
    As generated by the Morse Family
    - Alaska, circa 1960-1988 (Box-folder 10/1)
    - Alaska- Brochures and Pamphlets, Undated (Box-folder 10/2)
    - Alaska- Earthquake (Includes photographs), 1964 (Box-folder 10/3)
    - Alaska Purchase Centennial, 1967 (Box-folder 10/4)
    - Alaska: Tongass National Forest, 1978 (Box-folder 10/5)
    - Business Pulse Award- Awarded to David Morse, 1991 (Box-folder 10/6)
    - Classified Directories of Whatcom County Manufacturing Business and Professional Interest, published by the Bellingham American, 1923 (Box-folder 10/7)
    - Classified Directories of Whatcom County Manufacturing Business and Professional Interest, by the Bellingham Herald, 1934 (Box-folder 10/7)
    - Colt Firearms Historic Prints, undated (Box-folder 10/8)
    - Corporate Seal Label - Morse Hardware Company Ink Blotter, Undated (Box-folder 10/9)
    - State of Washington Supreme Court Cases: A.J. James, et.al. v. J.B. McMillian, et.al. (all are Whatcom Co. officials), 1920 (Box-folder 10/10)
    - Union Machinery & Supply Co. v. William McCush of Kendall Lumber & Shingle Co., 1918 (Box-folder 10/10)
    - Dan Erickson, Bloedel-Donovan Lumber Mills, Morse Hardware Co., Clift Motor Co., and Sherwin-Williams Co. v. Dick Perica, 1920 (Box-folder 10/10)
    - Design of 100 Year Anniversary of Morse Hardware Company Plaque, 1984 (Box-folder 10/11)
    - Land Titles, 1924; 1947 (Box-folder 10/12)